Raymond M. Song

(310) 755 4962 | raymondminsong@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/raymond-song-44a6a857 rs01247.github.io/my-portfolio/

Software engineer with a B.S. in Information Systems. Currently enrolled in the UC Irvine coding boot camp to broaden my knowledge and establish a path into the technology sector. I have cultivated a skill set based in strong communication and team work during the last 5 years of my career in B2B sales and logistics. Comfortable speaking to non-technical audiences about technical subject matter. Proven track record of achieving quarterly goals through team leadership. Now looking to pivot into software and web development to pursue a harbored passion for tech.

TECHNICAL CAPABILITIES

HTML5 / CSS3

JavaScript ES6

Node.js

Bootstrap 4.1

¡Query

AJAX

BUSINESS SKILLS

- Experience with speaking in public settings such as sales meetings or exhibiting at trade expos
- Background in project management and working in teams for quarterly programs
- History of producing well under pressure in a fast-paced sales environment
- Strong sense of professionalism displayed w/ customers and internally
- Very adaptable and open to changes in business plans/goals
- Client acquisition and relationship building

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine – Continuing Education

Irvine, CA

Certification, Web Development Coding Bootcamp

April 2018 - Present

University of California, Riverside

BS, Business Administration (Information Systems)

Riverside, CA September 2009 – August 2013

WORK EXPERIENCE

Market Development Manager

Orange, CA August 2017 - Present

Coca-Cola Refreshments

Territory growth of 23.63% in Gross Profit for Q3-Q4 (2017) and 47.87% year-to-date in 2018

- Portfolio includes "prestige" accounts such as LA Angels Stadium and Chapman University
- Year-to-date Net Revenue growth versus prior year for territory is at 11.30%
- Led district meetings and presented during branch visits w/ leadership
- Acquired 18 new accounts year-to-date

Account Manager - On Premise

Coca-Cola Refreshments

- Orange, CA Dec 2016 - August 2017
- Facilitated customer service needs with clients ranging from purchasing to work orders
- Met with businesses in person to increase brand portfolio by upselling solutions
- Tasked with introducing market to new products or brand programs
- Volume growth of 18% in cases sold during Q2 (2017)
- Focus in healthcare, hospitality, and retail sector

Fullerton, CA Feb 2015 - Dec 2016

Regional Account Manager (Northern/North East Territory)

ICC – A Structured Cabling Solutions Company

- Promoted existing customer base with certification programs and competitive bidding
- Serviced distribution channels through project quoting and inventory management
- Oversaw installation projects from planning stage to implementation
- Exhibited at industry-wide trade shows and vendor expos
- Territory growth of 18% in sales volume by distribution (2015)

Account Executive Santa Ana, CA June 2014 - Feb 2015

Main Street Business Capital

- Made an average of 140 daily outbound calls to prospective C-Suite Executives
- Specialized in construction, medical, and manufacturing industry
- Collected financial statements and handled initial underwriting
- Largest transaction to final funding: sales volume of \$90,000

Purchasing Agent

Inpac Trading Inc

Los Angeles, CA June 2013 – May 2014

- Negotiated with suppliers for improved pricing and shipment of products
- Regulated inventory to maintain efficient quantities and delivery times
- Sourced for new product lines by surveying market tendencies
- Predicted seasonal trends to anticipate purchasing variations